Ogooluwa Olutimilehin

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & FULL STACK DEVELOPER

An enthusiastic web developer with hands-on experience in creating interactive and responsive web applications, translating designs, interacting with Rest APIs, code versioning and using external libraries to create rich interfaces. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a productive team.

extremeworkbench@gmail.com +234 9121017814





GitHub

Experience

Mid-level Software Engineer

AtAfrica | 2024 - now

- Creating Live and Functional Websites and Applications from Scratch by Translating Wireframes
- Integrated third-party APIs and web services to add functionalities such as authentication, payment processing, and social media sharing.
- Collaborated closely with UX/UI designers to translate wireframes and mockups into pixelperfect, interactive web interfaces.

Junior Software Engineer

Securesoft Limited | 2022 - now

- Engaged in new business development, from a technical reference point in order to boost functionality and use-cases of software.
- Curated over 50 website changes to increase the user flow and understanding of all platform capabilities and features.
- Engaged in 100+ hours of Laravel training and PHP crash course with lead Technical officer.
- Assisted in product development and enhancements of current suite to boost engagement by 15%.
- Provided technical support for 10+ existing online products.

Junior Web Developer

Glam's Haven | 2020 - 2021

- Reduced customer support requests by 25% through the implementation of effective user feedback processes.
- Developed applications using React while managing the State through Redux and Redux-Forms saving 5+ hours of users' time.
- Increased web traffic by 23% through the development of engaging and effective user experiences.
- Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks(React), HTMLS, TailwindCss and SCSS, which improved user satisfaction by 47%.

Education

Bachelors in Information Technology

Eastern Mediterranean University | Bsc. Graduated with High Honors

PERSONAL PROJECTS

(visit https://ogooluwanick-portfolio.netlify.app/)

Inventools - Graduation Project

march 2021 - January 2022

- Created a database with MongoDB
- Created user login and registration
- Inventory functionality and Categorization for with using React Hooks
- · Page Routing using React Router
- · Utilized node/express for the backend
- Used Semantic UI for the dashboard/and data tables.
- Used CSS/SASS for styling and User Interface design.

Echos - Blog Webapp

January 2022 - February 2022

- Created a database with MongoDB
- · Made use of Google api for automatic login
- Created custom user login and registration.
- Made use of Redux for state management.
- · Page Routing using React Route.
- Utilized node/express for the backend.
- Used Material UI for the most major styling.
- Used SASS to make the site responsive

CURRENT INTERESTS

- Cloud Computing
- Micro Frontend Architecture
- · Cyber security
- Crypto

Skills

- Typescript, JavaScript
- CSS/SCSS/SASS
- ReactJs, React-Native, Redux (Redux Toolkit)
- Node.js
- · Git & Github
- Bootstrap/TailwindCss
- Laravel
- Data Visualisation (recharts, chart.js,three.js)
- Front-End Development

Licenses & Certifications

- Responsive Web Design
 - Issued May 2022 · No Expiration Date
 - Credential ID fcc971fa9f7-36ac-48d3-931e-537e2125f000
- Front End Development Libraries
 - o Issued July 2022 · No Expiration Date
 - Credential ID fcc971fa9f7-36ac-48d3-931e-537e2125f000
- Fundamentals of digital marketing
 - $\circ~$ Issued Apr 2022 \cdot No Expiration Date
 - o Credential ID PJN S8K V4K

DEPLOYMENT - CI/CD

- Netlify
- AWS
- Vercel